

Mario González Duarte

FRONT END DEVELOPER

Profile

Professional with 15+ years of experience in web development with a wide range of technical skills and a deep understanding of the latest technologies and trends in front end development. Ability to be decisive. Committed, dedicated, proactive and collaborative, with a predisposition both for teamwork and for helping and/or transmitting knowledge, providing mentoring and support. Always learning. In addition to development, I'm also interested in technical lead and front end architect roles.

Work Experience

Freelance

Madrid (Spain)

July 2022 - Present

Working on various projects related to web3 and blockchain technology.

- Design and development of a marketplace for Stream Dungeons NFT game, in Angular and SASS (https://nft.streamdungeons.com)
- Collaboration in the creation from scratch of a play-to-earn game, with React and SASS.
- Creation of a new online resume, in React and SASS.
- Update my expertise and skills in both Angular and React, taking training courses.

Front end developer and Architect, Copado Holdings Inc

Madrid (Spain)

May 2019 - July 2022

I worked on some of the best known applications of the company such as Data Templates, Pipeline and creating Value Stream Maps from scratch.

- Designed and developed generic Lightning Web Components to be reused by other developers in other parts of the application.
- Worked closely with the design department to convert the new company look and feel design in real CSS layouts.
- Refactoring and technical support to workmates.

Front end Architect, VASS

Madrid (Spain)

November 2017 - May 2019

Hired as a front end architect to collaborate in the design and development of different company projects Angular applications, several onboardings apps and various POC projects.

- Designed and developed an Angular library made up of components to be used by developers in their projects.
- Implemented a front end architecture in Ferrovial.
- Technical support to workmates and technical interviews to new candidates.

Javascript front end developer, Efron Consulting Inc

Boston, MA. USA

April 2015 - November 2017

- I worked at Isban developing different internal Santander USA bank applications.
- I designed and built a development environment which provided an architecture and a controlled environment to programming, in order to give crossover components and widgets to be used by developers in their projects.

Details

Madrid, Spain

magodu.pral@gmail.com

L +34 679 84 97 84

September 26th 1982

www.mariogonzalezduarte.es

Skills

Angular

React

Javascript

Typescript

Lightning Web Components

AngularJS

jQuery

Webpack

HTML5

CSS / SASS / LESS

Responsive Design

API REST

Git

Node JS

Jest

TDD

Agile Methodologies

Adobe Photoshop

Languages





Spanish

Enalish

Javascript front end developer, Adesis Netlife SL

Madrid, Spain October 2011 - April 2015

• Javascript developer in important customers such as BBVA Bancomer Mexico, Repsol, Bankia and Mapfre.

- At Mapfre, I worked in the establishment of a new and better front end architecture, developing new crossover component, initial developments (Zero versions) and experimental projects.
- Managed an small development group at Bankia.

Front end developer, Atmira Espacio de consultoría

November 2008 - October 2015 Madrid, Spain

I worked in Web applications for several Saving Banks at Confederación Española de Cajas de Ahorros (CECA).

Scholarship assistant, Cantabria Government Admin.

Santander, Spain August 2006 - October 2008

Scholarship assistant at Cantabria Education office (Spain), doing admin tasks as webmaster in the government educative site (Educantabria)

Education

High Degree Professional Training (CFGS) in Management Information Systems. Computer and Information Sciences.

IES Alisal. Santander, Spain

Other interesting data

Drive license B

Hobbies: photography, films and TV shows, music, traveling,

dancing, technology, reading

Linkedin: https://www.linkedin.com/in/mario-gonzalez-duarte

Github: https://github.com/magodu More info: www.mariogonzalezduarte.es

Courses

Clean Code

NodeJS

Closures

React Angular

LWC Typescript

AngularJS

Memory Leaks

Polymer

Web design .NET

Photoshop E-commerce

Java